# **Daniel J. Marchetto**

(412) 720-3173 daniel.marchetto@gatech.edu daniel-marchetto.github.io GitHub: daniel-marchetto LinkedIn: daniel-marchetto

Behavioral and Data Scientist. My current project involves utilizing my skills to learn the experience and motivations of graduate students on r/GradSchool. This project includes topic modeling, sentiment analysis, and online surveying.

# **EDUCATION**

Doctor of Philosophy in Public Policy, Georgia Institute of Technology Specialization: Science and Technology Policy	Expected 2022
Master of Science in Computational Science and Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology	Expected 2022
Master of Science in Statistics, Georgia Institute of Technology	2021
Master of Public Policy, Arizona State University	2018
Bachelor of Science in Psychology, Carnegie Mellon University	2016

### **PUBLICATIONS**

Topic Classification of Electric Vehicle Consumer Experience with Transformer-based Deep Learning, *Patterns 2021* Ha, S., Marchetto, D.J., Dharur, S., Asensio, O.I.

Extracting User Behavior at Electric Vehicle Charging Stations with Transformer Deep Learning Models, *CARMA 2020*Marchetto, D.J., Ha, S., Dharur, S., Asensio, O.I.

## RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant August 2018 — May 2021

Dr. Julia Melkers Georgia Tech

Analyzed themes from a series of phone interviews with computer science graduate students to learn about elements of self-efficacy. Designed the structure and elements of a large-scale survey including the development of a novel self-efficacy scale. Analyzed literature relating to faculty career development and online education.

Dr. Omar Isaac Asensio Georgia Tech

Designed and implemented survey to crowd-source partial labeling of a text corpus. Implemented transformer classification architectures in Python to fully label text corpus. Analyzed correlates of the labeled corpus using fixed-effect models in R. Analyzed effects of HUD funding on electricity consumption in Albany, GA with difference-in-difference models. Propensity score and genetic matching we utilized to construct the control group.

# **Smart Community Corps Fellow**

May 2019 — September 2019

Institute for People and Technology

Georgia Tech

Graduate Fellow in project to improve data connectivity and transparency in the City of Albany, GA. Designed geohub website for sharing city data publicly utilizing ESRI's online architecture. Consulted on design of SQL database for linkage of city records relating to economic development and utility consumption.

Graduate Research Assistant January 2017 — July 2018

Dr. Lily Hsueh Arizona State

Conducted literature search on firm-level carbon emission reduction and its relation to corporate self-governance. Collected firm-level emission data and Twitter data from S&P 500 corporations using Thomson Reuters and Python. Analyzed trends between Twitter postings and corporate emissions using classification and regression techniques in R.

Research Intern

Republic Services

June 2017 — August 2017

Phoenix, AZ

Managed project to analyze sources of turnover in material recycling facilities. Conducted phone and on-site interviews with

## **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

key stakeholders. Presented results to members of upper management.

Co-Instructor	Research Design in Policy Science	Spring 2022
Graduate Teaching Assistant	Engineering Ethics	Fall 2021
	Big Data and Public Policy	Spring 2020
	Economics and Public Policy	Fall 2017, Spring 2018

### **SKILLS**

Tools and Languages	R, Python, Julia, SQL, Git, ᡌᠮᡓX
Analytic Techniques	Regression, Classification, Clustering, Structural Equation Modeling, Multilevel Modeling,
	Experimental Design, Survey Design, Psychometrics, Text Analysis